# **Evgenii Smazanovich**

Telephone: 07865 508 114

Email: <a href="mailto:smazanovich@hotmail.com">smazanovich@hotmail.com</a>

Orchard Cottage, 102a Main Street, Higham on the Hill, CV13 6AJ

## **Personal Profile**

A professional, ambitious and active Merchant Navy Officer with 8 years' experience onboard chemical, product and crude oil tankers including aframax, suezmax, VLCC and short-range types operating worldwide and engaged in global trade. Have experience with dry bulk cargoes such as grain and ore. Holder of the Chief Officer Certificate of Competence and STCW certificates for the management level on tankers. Current student at the Institute of Chartered Shipbrokers (London Branch) and Member of the Merchant Navy Association. Now looking for a career change in the commercial, financial and energy sectors.

# **Key Skills**

- Ability to prioritise work based on urgency and importance; work well under pressure
- Management experience
- Fluent in English, Russian and Ukrainian
- Attention to detail, numerical accuracy, multitasking
- Analytical Skills; knowledge of energy and commodity markets (oil, ore/metals, grain)
- Ability to work well with others
- Sensitivity and understanding; working with multinational vendors and stakeholders
- Patience and the ability to remain calm in stressful situations

# **Employment History**

## 2016 — Present

# Second Officer, Columbia Ship Management, promoted to a Chief Officer

- First point of contact in ship-to-ship and ship-to-shore communications.
  Receiving verbal instructions from ship operators, followed by receiving and processing voyage orders via email.
- Calculating cargo figures and preparing stowage plans; sending stowage plans, last three cargoes forms and Q88 to ship operators.
  Using UTIs and dipsticks, tank gauging systems, ASTM tables and loading computers to obtain ullages, soundings and temperatures of cargo to prepare ullage OBQ reports, find water traces, calculate Gross and Net Cargo figures in air and vacuum. Preparing NoRs, Letters of Protest, maintaining statements of facts and logging events, preparing hourly pumping rate and pressure logs.
  Calculating official gross port stay and net cargo operation time figures.
- Communicating ships' position updates, ETAs, daily/voyage speeds, distances, additional remarks, start/end of sea passage times using reporting software, email and phone or radio to agents, pilots, terminal representatives, owners, charterers and brokers.
- Directly ordering pilots, mooring teams, vendors on handysize tankers; On larger tankers, in liaison with agents.
- Voyage planning, appraisal, execution and monitoring. This includes addressing load lines zones, draft restrictions (departure, arrival, channel, bar, berth, brakish water etc), weather/current factors, security risks, ice areas, environmentally sensitive areas (e.g. ECA areas, EU waters and ports, Chinese national emission

- control areas, Turkish sulphur content limits of marine fuels, ballast exchange special regulation areas like Norway, Black Sea, Turkey).
- Checking, scanning, copying, emailing and filing of cargo commercial documentation.
- Understanding of all types of charter parties and clauses, chartering terms, fixtures, recaps, market offers.
- Knowledge of Baltic Exchange trade routes for wet, gas and dry bulk markets.
- Organising toolbox talks, senior officers' meetings. Managing crewmembers and assigning duties. Leading internal HSE audits. Ensuring compliance with HSE oil majors requirements, OCIMF SIRE VIQ, monitoring vetting companies inspection reports and ensuring that ships don't have correspondent noncompliances.
- Calculating annual EEOI and logging it into Energy Management plan.

## 2013-2016

# **Third Officer, Columbia Shipmanagement**

- Assisting the Captain and higher officers.
- Health, Safety and Quality meetings secretariat. Preparing meetings minutes, reports and suggestions for improvement. Taking part in PSC, Vetting and internal audits.
- Creating crew members' wage accounts, processing international travel expenses, calculating monthly and final payrolls, overtime calculations, issuing cash advances.
- Port of call clearance documentation on arrival and departure. Processing and completion of electronic data interchange forms, proficient in Microsoft Office.
- Administration of online forms, checklists, documents. Uploading documents into electronic data interchange services.

#### 2010-2013

# Cadetship Apprenticeship with Columbia Shipmanagement, Tranship, Ukrainian State Ferry Service and Ukrainian Hydrography Organisation

- Replacing IALA Cardinal and Lateral buoys.
- Supervising and assisting Captain and Chief Officer in dry bulk cargo operations. Transferring wheat and ore from the Black Sea to Mediterranean.
- Assisting passengers on ferries; providing quality customer support.

#### **Education & Qualification**

#### 2021 Institute of Chartered Shipbrokers

Undertaking Professional Qualifying Examinations.

Completed courses include: Shipping Business; Economics of Sea Transport and International Trade; Tanker Chartering

## 2016 London School of English, London

Intensive Advanced English and IELTS Courses — Grade: C1

# 2015 CKK Academy, Buxtehude, Germany

Bridge Resource Management, Bridge Team Management, Ship Handling, Crisis Management

# 2009 – 2013 Kerch State Maritime Technological University, Crimea

BSc (Hons) Engineering-Navigation (Nautical Science) — Grade: Honours Student of the Year and Awarded Presidential Scholarship for Achievement in Maritime Studies

## **Certifications** Audits and Follow-up

Emergency preparedness and response Maritime Resource Management